{
	"cards": [
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-25-tag-multiple-choice-card-1",
			"front": {
				"choices": [
					"determine the vehicleâ€™s speed at the time of impact.",
					"assess the severity of the third collision of the crash.",
					"identify contact points and predict potential injuries.",
					"recognize if the driver hit the brakes before impact."
				],
				"question": "Evaluation of the interior of a crashed motor vehicle during extrication will allow the EMT to:",
				"source": "See Blunt Trauma"
			},
			"back": "identify contact points and predict potential injuries."
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-25-tag-multiple-choice-card-2",
			"front": {
				"choices": [
					"be involved in trauma prevention programs.",
					"have general surgeons in-house 24 hours a day.",
					"be able to stabilize patients before transferring to a higher level facility.",
					"have access to an emergency physician within 30 minutes."
				],
				"question": "In contrast to a Level III trauma center, a Level I trauma center must:",
				"source": "See Management: Transport and Destinations"
			},
			"back": "have general surgeons in-house 24 hours a day."
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-25-tag-multiple-choice-card-3",
			"front": {
				"choices": [
					"multiple rib fractures.",
					"coughing up blood.",
					"vomiting blood.",
					"an irregular pulse."
				],
				"question": "Signs of a pulmonary blast injury include:",
				"source": "See Blast Injuries"
			},
			"back": "coughing up blood."
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-25-tag-multiple-choice-card-4",
			"front": {
				"choices": [
					"bilateral hip fractures usually occur when an elderly person falls.",
					"any fall in the elderly is considered to be high-energy trauma.",
					"osteoporosis can cause a fracture as a result of a fall from a standing position.",
					"elderly patients who fall usually have a secondary head injury."
				],
				"question": "When assessing an elderly patient who fell, it is important to remember that:",
				"source": "See Blunt Trauma"
			},
			"back": "osteoporosis can cause a fracture as a result of a fall from a standing position."
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-25-tag-multiple-choice-card-5",
			"front": {
				"choices": [
					"be used with or without a shoulder harness.",
					"prevent a second collision inside the car.",
					"prevent the driver from sustaining head trauma.",
					"decrease the severity of deceleration injuries."
				],
				"question": "Airbags are designed to:",
				"source": "See Blunt Trauma"
			},
			"back": "decrease the severity of deceleration injuries."
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-25-tag-multiple-choice-card-6",
			"front": {
				"choices": [
					"transport the survivors only if they have injuries or complain of pain.",
					"rapidly assess only the survivors who have experienced obvious trauma.",
					"allow the survivors to refuse transport if they have no obvious injuries.",
					"suspect that all living occupants experienced the same serious trauma."
				],
				"question": "If one or more occupants in the same vehicle are killed in a crash, the EMT should:",
				"source": "See Blunt Trauma"
			},
			"back": "suspect that all living occupants experienced the same serious trauma."
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-25-tag-multiple-choice-card-7",
			"front": {
				"choices": [
					"Elevation of the lower extremities",
					"Early administration of oxygen",
					"Intravenous fluid administration",
					"Rapid transport to a trauma center"
				],
				"question": "Which of the following interventions is the MOST critical to the outcome of a patient with multisystem trauma?",
				"source": "See Multisystem Trauma"
			},
			"back": "Rapid transport to a trauma center"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-25-tag-multiple-choice-card-8",
			"front": {
				"choices": [
					"the way in which traumatic injuries occur.",
					"the detection of less obvious life-threatening injuries.",
					"a predictable pattern that leads to serious injuries.",
					"your awareness and concern for potentially serious underlying injuries."
				],
				"question": "The index of suspicion is MOST accurately defined as:",
				"source": "See Introduction"
			},
			"back": "your awareness and concern for potentially serious underlying injuries."
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-25-tag-multiple-choice-card-9",
			"front": {
				"choices": [
					"Dismounted seats",
					"Deployment of the airbag",
					"Intrusion into the vehicle",
					"Steering wheel collapse"
				],
				"question": "Which of the following findings would be LEAST suggestive of the presence of high-energy trauma?",
				"source": "See Blunt Trauma"
			},
			"back": "Deployment of the airbag"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-25-tag-multiple-choice-card-10",
			"front": {
				"choices": [
					"exit wounds caused by the bullet are usually small.",
					"the bullet may tumble or ricochet within the body.",
					"the area of damage is usually smaller than the bullet.",
					"the caliber of the bullet is frequently unknown."
				],
				"question": "Internal injuries caused by gunshot wounds are difficult to predict because:",
				"source": "See Penetrating Trauma"
			},
			"back": "the bullet may tumble or ricochet within the body."
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-25-tag-multiple-choice-card-11",
			"front": {
				"choices": [
					"index of suspicion.",
					"potential energy.",
					"kinetic energy.",
					"mechanism of injury."
				],
				"question": "When assessing the interior of a crashed motor vehicle for damage, you are gathering information regarding the:",
				"source": "See Energy and Trauma"
			},
			"back": "mechanism of injury."
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-25-tag-multiple-choice-card-12",
			"front": {
				"choices": [
					"Collapsed dashboard",
					"Intrathoracic hemorrhage",
					"Deformed steering wheel",
					"Caved-in passenger door"
				],
				"question": "Which of the following would MOST likely occur as the direct result of the second collision in a motor vehicle crash?",
				"source": "See Blunt Trauma"
			},
			"back": "Deformed steering wheel"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-25-tag-multiple-choice-card-13",
			"front": {
				"choices": [
					"has a bleeding disorder or takes anticoagulant medications and has any blunt or penetrating injury.",
					"has a systolic blood pressure of less than 110 mm Hg or a heart rate greater than 110 beats/min.",
					"was involved in a motor vehicle crash in which another patient in the same vehicle was killed.",
					"has a GCS score of less than or equal to 13 with a mechanism attributed to trauma."
				],
				"question": "According to the American College of Surgeons Committee on Trauma (ACS-COT), an adult trauma patient should be transported to the highest level of trauma center if he or she:",
				"source": "See Management: Transport and Destinations"
			},
			"back": "has a GCS score of less than or equal to 13 with a mechanism attributed to trauma."
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-25-tag-multiple-choice-card-14",
			"front": {
				"choices": [
					"potential energy.",
					"work.",
					"kinetic energy.",
					"latent energy."
				],
				"question": "Force acting over a distance is the definition of:",
				"source": "See Energy and Trauma"
			},
			"back": "work."
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-25-tag-multiple-choice-card-15",
			"front": {
				"choices": [
					"cavitation.",
					"conversion.",
					"capitation.",
					"congruent."
				],
				"question": "The phenomenon of pressure waves emanating from the bullet, causing damage remote from its path, is known as:",
				"source": "See Penetrating Trauma"
			},
			"back": "cavitation."
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-25-tag-multiple-choice-card-16",
			"front": {
				"choices": [
					"remains within the vehicle.",
					"experiences multiple impacts.",
					"is wearing only a lap belt.",
					"is ejected or partially ejected."
				],
				"question": "A driver involved in a rollover motor vehicle crash will MOST likely experience serious injuries or death if he or she:",
				"source": "See Blunt Trauma"
			},
			"back": "is ejected or partially ejected."
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-25-tag-multiple-choice-card-17",
			"front": {
				"choices": [
					"the height of the fall.",
					"the primary impact point.",
					"the speed of the fall.",
					"the surface struck."
				],
				"question": "Factors that should be considered when assessing a patient who has fallen include all of the following, EXCEPT:",
				"source": "See Blunt Trauma"
			},
			"back": "the speed of the fall."
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-25-tag-multiple-choice-card-18",
			"front": {
				"choices": [
					"potential energy.",
					"kinetic energy.",
					"latent energy.",
					"converted energy."
				],
				"question": "The energy of a moving object is called:",
				"source": "See Energy and Trauma"
			},
			"back": "kinetic energy."
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-25-tag-multiple-choice-card-19",
			"front": {
				"choices": [
					"use a demand valve to ventilate the patient.",
					"suspect an accompanying cardiac tamponade.",
					"avoid giving oxygen under positive pressure.",
					"administer large amounts of intravenous fluid."
				],
				"question": "When treating a patient who experienced a pulmonary blast injury, you should:",
				"source": "See Blast Injuries"
			},
			"back": "avoid giving oxygen under positive pressure."
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-25-tag-multiple-choice-card-20",
			"front": {
				"choices": [
					"doubles.",
					"triples.",
					"is not affected.",
					"quadruples."
				],
				"question": "When the speed of a motor vehicle doubles, the amount of kinetic energy:",
				"source": "See Energy and Trauma"
			},
			"back": "quadruples."
		}
	],
	"category": {
		"value": "chapter-25",
		"label": "Chapter 25"
	},
	"tags": [
		{
			"value": "multiple-choice",
			"label": "Multiple Choice"
		}
	]
}